大家好 我是黛布拉·拉德克利夫博士
Welcome, everyone. I'm Dr. Debra Radcliffe.
今天我要帮你们清理废物抽屉
And today I'm going to help you clean out your junk drawer.
当然了 我指的是你们的情感废物抽屉
Of course, I'm talking about an emotional junk drawer
我们要把里面所有痛苦 恐惧和愤怒都清理掉
where we store all the pain, fear, anger that shapes us.
有人想分享一下 今天来这里的原因吗
Who would like to share why they're here?
这个人今天参加高中拍卖会没戴眼镜
This one didn't have her glasses at the high-school auction.
她以为自己在竞拍一个储物盒
Thought she was bidding on a home organizer.
多么幸运的错误
And what a lucky mistake.
在哥伦比亚 我们根本没有这种活动
In Colombia, we never get to do things like this.
我参加过的唯一一个讨论会
The only time that I ever went to a seminar
是大家讨论当你的手被绑住的时候
was how to escape the trunk of a car
要怎么从车后备箱里逃出来
when your hands are tied behind your back.
大家都站起来吧
All right, everybody. On your feet.
说起来 我以为这个活动
Okay. You know, I-I sort of thought
-是那种坐在这乖乖听讲座的类型 -是啊
- this was a "sit here and listen" kind of a thing. - Yeah.
或者说 婚姻也是这样
Or as I call it, marriage.
我丈夫呢
Where's my husbands at?
最尴尬的时候笑一笑总是好的
It's good to laugh at what makes us most uncomfortable.
但是接下来的三小时 大家都必须投入进来
But the next three hours will require active participation.
我们都站开一点
Let's clear a little space for ourselves.
你不是说这个活动只有45分钟吗
You said this was a 45-minute talk.
那又怎么了 我估计错误了
So what? I was wrong.
怎么 难道你不想坐在这里
What, is there a place that you'd rather be
跟你的家人好好的谈心吗
than connecting with your family?
你居然在橄榄球周日问我这种问题
You're really asking this question on Football Sunday?
这些人都放弃了他们的橄榄球比赛
All these men here gave up their football today.
谢谢你 米奇尔 谢谢你的牺牲
Thank you, Mitchell, for your sacrifice.
你可知道为了这个活动我都没去成农夫市场
Hey, you know what? I'm missing a farmer's market to be here,
我刚才好想让自己变得更基了
so...yeah, I just made it gayer.
拒绝打开自己的情感废物抽屉很正常
It's perfectly normal to resist opening your emotional junk drawer.
我在第一章《装个把手》里说过
I address that in chapter one -- "Hey, get a handle on it".
我们来做个有趣的活动放松一下吧
Why don't we start with a fun activity to loosen everyone up?
我才不管什么放松 我不想玩这种游戏
I don't care how loose we get, I'm not spilling my guts
假装台灯是我母亲 跟它说话
to some table lamp pretending it's my mother.
我不会要求你这么做的 杰
And I won't ask you to, Jay.
那种荒谬的做法给情感治疗抹黑了
That kind of silliness gives therapy a bad name.
我们要玩一个叫"老虎摇滚明星兔子"的游戏
We are going to play a game called Tiger, Rock star, Bunny.
我知道了
I got this.
嫁给老虎 杀了兔子
Uh, marry the tiger, kill the bunny?
不是这么玩的
That's not my game.
但我说老虎的时候
When I call out tiger,
你们要变成一只凶猛的老虎
you will become a ferocious tiger.
当我说摇滚明星的时候
When I call out rock star,
你们要变成一个摇滚明星
You will be... a major rocker.
我说兔子的时候 你们要
And when I call out bunny, you will be --
回家去了 再见
Halfway home. Goodbye.
走吧
Oh, yeah, go ahead,
不过别忘了 我们可没签婚前协议
but don't forget that we don't have a prenup.
那就开始吧
Let's get started.
老虎
Tiger!
真是可笑 我觉得我需要大喝一杯
Feel ridiculous. I might need booze for this.
我也需要
Oh, me likey that idea.
我们可不适合这个
We are not cut out for this.
你可别想跟我比
You can't compare yourself to me.
我毕竟出演过《猫》
I was in "Cats".
没人敢跟你比 小卡
No one's comparing themselves to you, Cam.
摇滚明星
Rock star.
你做得很好 菲尔
Looking good, Phil.
我在高中的时候赢了幻想吉他比赛
I won an air-guitar contest in high school.
你肯定靠这个交到了很多幻想女朋友
Bet that got you a lot of air girlfriends.
杰 别这样 这多好玩啊
Come on, Jay. Loosen up. It's fun.
你在干什么 老爸
What the hell is that, dad?
弹手风琴
Playing an accordion.
你应该是个摇滚明星啊
Supposed to be a rock star.
你不应该弹弹吉他什么的吗
I think you should do, like, a guitar or something.
我只会弹手风琴
I only know how to play the accordion.
你去挑剔米奇尔吧 他还在吹笛子呢
Pick on Mitchell. He's playing a flute.
我倒希望他吹的是笛子[箫]
At least I hope he is.
他们为什么要不让你待家里
So, why did they need you out of the house?
他们说要弄一个什么疗法
They said it was some sort of therapy,
但是我觉得他们是专门为老妈准备的
but part of me thinks it's an intervention for Mom.
学校怎么样
So, how's school?
在我们的牛顿机械课上
Well, in my newtonian mechanics class,
我们学了怎么计算
we're learning how to calculate
自由坠落物体的速度
the velocity of free falling objects in a...
上学很辛苦
School's hard.
好吧
So, anyways, um...
我做了一件坏事 我需要你的建议
I sort of did something and I need your advice,
但是我不想听你一直批判我
but I don't want a lot of judgment and criticism.
那你来找我干什么
And you came to me?
你一直很理智
Yeah, you've always had such a strong sense
知道什么是对是错
of what's right and wrong.
-你知道的 -我找了个高中小男友
- You always know what-- - I have a high-school boy toy.
什么 谁啊
What?! Who?
卢克那个书呆子朋友罗本
It's Luke's dorky friend Reuben.
我觉得太羞耻了
I feel so ashamed.
天哪 他不是只有八岁吗 你胆子太大了
Oh, my God. You should be. Isn't he, like, 8?
不 他有16又3/4岁了
No, he's 16 and 3/4,
而且他基本每两周就要刮一次胡子
and he has to shave almost every two weeks.
怎么会这样呢 你上的可是加州理工啊
How did you let this happen? You go to Caltech.
你应该跟你这个年纪的书呆子约会
You're surrounded by age-appropriate dorks.
我知道 但那时我待在家
I know, but I was home and still feeling sad
一直在为了桑杰甩掉我这事伤心
about Sanjay breaking up with me,
而学校的压力又这么大
and it's overwhelming here.
聪明的人太多了
There are so many brilliant people,
罗本却把我当一个偶像
and Reuben idolizes me.
我想我可能需要一个人陪我
I guess I just kind of needed that,
所以我让他亲了我
so I let him kiss me...
还做了点其它的事情[露胸]
and a little bit of this.
我太软弱了 这是我遇到过最糟糕的事
I'm so weak. I can't imagine anything worse.
我跟安迪搞上了
I hooked up with Andy.
什么
What?!
订婚了的那个安迪吗
Engaged Andy?
我知道他订婚了 我们那天在某个人房里
I know. We were all alone at this house
老爸特意把房间布置得很性感
that dad had set up to be sexy--
老爸专门给你们弄的吗
Dad made it sexy for you?!
不 是给买家弄的 但是当时只有我和安迪
No, no, for the buyer, but Andy and I were alone,
于是我们就"哇"了
a-and suddenly...bam.
"哇"
Bam?
"哇"是指你们上床了
"Bam" as in sex
还是像罗本解开我胸罩的时候说了声"哇"一样
or "Bam" as in what Reuben shouted when he unhooked my bra?
这个话题就不要继续了
Let's just leave it at "Bam."
看看我们俩
Look at us.
我不知道自己应该是什么感觉
I don't even know what to feel right now.
羞耻 罪恶 恐惧
Shame, guilt, fear.
这些都是一些
These are just some of the things
我们年轻时
we shoved in the back of our junk drawers
扔进废物抽屉的情绪
when we were young.
下面这个活动出自第三章
This exercise comes from chapter three,
《恐怖的噩梦与过期的奶油》
"Scary dreams, expired creams".
那两个我都有
Oh, I have both of those.
这个姿势可能看起来不正常
This may seem unconventional,
但是它有助于你们释放痛苦的回忆
but it helps access painful memories...
真不错
This is nice.
不 我觉得很诡异
No, it's not. It's weird.
你今天很紧张 我的小宝贝
You're so tense today, my little baby.
你在担心什么
What are you worried about?
我们看起来像傻瓜一样
Us looking like idiots.
我们可是这里的明星
What? We're superstars here.
我们结婚最久 有三个快乐的孩子
Married the longest, three happy children,
其中一个还前途远大
one with a bright future.
你说得对
You're right.
我们能赢
We're gonna win this thing.
这又不是什么比赛
It's not a competition.
对啊 我们已经赢了
Exactly. We have this in the bag.
米奇尔和小卡只要一到选餐厅
Mitchell and Cam fall apart
就会吵得不可开交
if they've got to pick a restaurant,
歌洛莉亚只会吼我爸
and all Gloria ever does is yell at my dad.
是啊 我可不想当你爸
Yeah, I'd really hate to be your dad right now.
告诉我你所有的想法
Now, tell me everything that you're thinking.
我在想除了这个破玩意儿
I'm thinking about all that other stuff we could've bid on
拍卖会上本能拍到的别的东西
at that auction instead of this nonsense.
和拉里·金[著名访谈家]共进午餐 搭乘警车
Lunch with Larry King. A ride along in a cop car.
听说警察还附赠用电枪电人的体验
I heard they let you tase someone.
杰 现在的治疗很重要
Jay, this is important.
黛布拉医生说了这样对我们有好处
Dr. Debra said that this is good for us.
闭上你的眼睛
Now close your eyes.
我为什么要闭上眼睛
Why should I close my eyes?
因为我不想你从那个角度看我的脖子
Because I don't like you looking up at my neck like that.
我上次从那个角度自拍的时候
The other day, I took a selfie from down there
还以为在跟我奶奶视频
and I thought that I was face timing with my grandmother.
我记得我妈进噜商店
I wemember my mom went into the store
却把伦家忘在了卡车后座
and left me all alone in the back of a twuck.
你一定要学小孩子说话吗
Okay, do you have to do the baby talk?
我小时候发不出R的音
I couldn't pronounce my R's when I was younger
其他孩子都笑话我 米奇尔
and the other children made fun of me, Mitchell.
伦家超怕怕的
It was very twaumatic.
妈 妈咪 你在哪里
Mom? Mommy? Where are you?
好吧 我已经开始麻木了
All right, I'm -- I'm starting to lose feeling.
是我压到你的腿了吗
Oh, am I squishing your legs?
不 我是指我们的关系
No, I meant in our relationship.
好了 我们得定个计划
All right, we need a game plan here.
我爸和我姐都在这里
My dad and sister are here.
我们尽量低调点 随便挑点无关紧要的说
Let's keep a low profile -- light and surfacy.
那我们不是浪费了一个绝佳的
But aren't we wasting a great opportunity
了解我的机会吗
to learn more about me?
我们不要拿自己来娱乐大众
We are not gonna be the sideshow gay couple.
好吗 不要讲太私人的事
Okay, nothing too personal.
别把闺房之乐拿出来说
For god's sake, no bedroom stuff.
我们代表的是同性恋这个团体
We're representing a community.
你们俩交流得如何了
And how are you two doing here?
我们很好 交流毫无障碍
We're very good, very healthy.
-我们很开心 -是的
- Very happy. - Yes.
小卡 你想换个姿势吗
Cam, would you like to switch positions?
我不能提这种事
I'm not allowed to talk about that.
你们俩交流得怎样了
How's it going here with you two?
不好 他连试都不想试
Not good. He's not even trying.
感觉你卡在抽屉里了
Sounds like you're stuck in that drawer.
感觉你卡在那个比喻里了
Sounds like you're stuck in that metaphor.
是什么令你裹足不前 杰
What's holding you back, Jay?
我不想这么被人抱着
I don't like to be held like this.
为什么呢 会让你感觉自己很脆弱吗
Why? 'cause you feel vulnerable?
我不知道
I don't know.
这让我想起了一些事
It just... reminds me of something.
说出来吧 你在这里很安全
Go with that. You're safe here.
我不想觉得这里很安全
I don't want to be safe here.
我不想聊关于这些的事
I don't want to talk about this.
关于什么的 告诉我
About what? Tell me.
我的狗跑掉再也没回来的时候
It's like the time my mom held me like this
我妈妈就是这么抱着我的
when my dog ran away and never came back.
她一直跟我说他们不知道它怎么跑掉的
She kept telling me they didn't know how it got out,
但我知道
but I knew.
我没关门 都是我的错
I left the gate open. It was my fault.
是我没仔细检查
I lost checkers.
我受不了了
I can't take this.
等等 刚刚发生了什么事
Wait, what -- what just happened?
不知道 我想他只是不习惯表达内心情感
I don't know. I think he's not used to feeling emotions.
这对他来说有点过了
Maybe it was too much for him.
不 不 这是好事
No, no, this is good.
有些人的废物抽屉太满了
Some people's junk drawers are so full,
想打开都很难
it's a struggle to open them.
他刚是不是捂着胸口
W-was he holding his chest?
-是啊 -有点不对劲
- Se. - Something seemed wong.
杰 你没事吧 我是歌洛莉亚
Jay, are you okay? It's Gloria.
爸 爸 你没事吧
Dad. Dad, come on.
门锁上了
Ay, it's locked.
爸 快开门
D-dad, open up.
稍等 我这里有曲别针
Hang on, I got a paperclip.
小心点 他很脆弱
Be careful. He's very raw.
加油 加油 加油
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
杰
Jay!
我还很伤心呢
I'm still sad.
你宁愿躲进洗手间里
You prefer to hide in the bathroom
也不愿正视自己的情感
than to deal with your emotions!
歌洛莉亚 这有什么大不了的
Gloria, what's the big deal?
重点在于我们要在一起抚养小孩
The big deal is that we're raising a child together,
而你有机会
and you have a chance
把他变得跟那两个不一样
to make him different than those two.
-你说啥 -说我们吗
- Hello. - Us?
抱歉 我们怎么不好了
I'm sorry. What's wrong with us?
我会为了你们挡子弹
I'd take a bullet for you,
但你们俩稍微有点神经质
but you two are kind of neurotic.
-我们没有神经质 -有人说我们神经质吗
- We're not neurotic. - Do people say that we're neurotic?
他们没有这么说 是吧
They don't say that, do they?
对 对
Yes. Yes.
所有的垃圾都想从抽屉里出来
All the junk wants to come out of the drawer.
-你能感觉到吗 -我能
- Can you feel it? - I can.
不 杰什么都没感觉到
No, Jay doesn't feel anything.
我感觉到很多东西
I feel lots of things.
因为错过比赛而生气
Annoyed that I'm missing my game,
-因为匹兹堡钢人赢而开心 -比分多少了
- joy that the Steelers are winning. - Oh, what is the score?
我们在这里不谈橄榄球
We're not gonna talk about football here!
歌洛莉亚说得没错
Gloria's right.
我们应该聊点更深入的
We should talk about deeper things
比如14年到6年[14比6]的尴尬岁月
like those awkward years between 14 to 6.
太好了
Oh. Yes.
我们什么时候可以开始聊
When do we get to talk about the dumb things
我们老公做过的蠢事
that our husbands do?
歌洛莉亚 谢谢你 很高兴你这么说
Gloria, thank you. I'm glad you said that.
不用谢 总得有人帮你
You're welcome. At least somebody's helping.
因为那种语言会产生反作用
Because that kind of language is counterproductive.
真糟糕
Oh, snap.
下一个练习能教会我们如何有建设性地
This next exercise will teach us how to communicate our needs
不伤人地表达自己的需求
in a constructive and non-threatening manner.
我们一直都这样
We do that all the time.
非常有建设性地交流
Very constructively communicated.
有哪一对夫妇能帮我
Would one of my couples like to help me demonstrate
给大家展示一下吗
for the rest of the group?
有 我们愿意帮忙
Yes, we would. We'd love to help.
-这算什么低调 -肯定会很有趣
- How is this low profile? - Oh, come on, it'll fun.
-把椅子搬过来 小卡 -好的
- Your chair, please, Cam. - Sure.
-面朝这边 -谢谢
- Face this way. - Thank you.
现在我希望你们都能想一个
Now, I'd like you both to think of a behavior
你希望伴侣能够改变的行为
of your partner's that you would like to change.
但是要避免使用
But we're going to avoid phrases
"你总是" "你从不[永不]"这种词
like "You always" and "You never",
而换成表达自己感受的语言
and instead put it in terms of how we feel.
好
Okay.
米奇尔 你先开始
Mitch, you'll start.
好吧
Okay.
有时候 我希望你能少穿点蓝色
Sometimes, I wish you wouldn't wear blue so much
因为我嫉妒你穿得这么好看
because I feel jealous that you look so good in it.
小卡 告诉米奇你是否听到了
Now, Cam, let Mitch know if you heard him
以及你是否能做到
and if you feel you can do that.
-我听到了 -好的
- I did hear that. - Okay.
我也会尽量少穿蓝色
And I will try to wear less blue.
很好 很好
Very good. Very good.
也许你能稍微讲得深入一点
Maybe dig a little deeper in the drawer.
有些时候你和饮料的时候
Well, sometimes when you don't use a coaster
没有用杯托
with a -- a drink,
我会很焦虑 因为我喜欢我们的家居用品
I get anxious because I love our furniture
那是我们一起买的
and we bought it together.
真暖心 我听到了
Aww, that's very sweet. I hear that.
我会尽量多用杯托的
And I'm gonna try and use a coaster more.
很好 你们做得都很棒
Okay. Excellent, both of you.
米奇 继续
Mitch, keep going.
有些时候你离开房间时
Yeah, so, uh...sometimes when you leave the room
会不关灯 我感觉...
and you don't turn off the lights, I just feel --
有没搞错 又提这个
Seriously? That again?
别这么认真
Surfacy.
我告诉过你别再跟我唠叨关灯的事
Well, I told you not to harp on me about the lights.
因为这是我第一次听你
Oh, because this is the first time
提到杯托的事
that I'm hearing about the coasters.
看看吧
Here we go.
别在那里幸灾乐祸
Okay, I don't appreciate the smirking.
我听到了 米奇尔
I hear you, Mitchell,
下次我会趁你没看到的时候幸灾乐祸的
and I will try to smirk when you're not looking.
我觉得如果安迪没订婚 我们可能会有机会的
I feel like if Andy weren't engaged, we'd have a chance.
如果罗本稍微大一点儿
And if Reuben were just a little bit older
而且不用穿矫正鞋的话
and didn't wear prescription shoes --
-还是很恶心 -我知道
- It'd still be gross. - I know.
-我们该怎么办 -我们应该叫停[结束]
- What are we gonna do? - We should both just end it.
我不要自杀
I am not killing myself.
-不 我说的是分手 天哪
- No! Break up with them. Oh, God.
你值得找一个没有订婚的人
You deserve somebody that isn't engaged to somebody else.
对啊 你也值得找一个
Yeah, and you deserve to be with someone
没跟卢克一起洗过澡的人
who didn't take baths with Luke.
我已经提过一次分手了
I already tried to dump him once.
希望这次能真的甩掉他
Hopefully it'll go better this time.
我受够了这样藏着掖着谈恋爱
Look, I'm sick of hiding our love.
-如果你觉得我丢了你的脸 -没错
- If you're ashamed of me -- - I am.
-那我们最好分手 -赞成
- Then maybe we should break up. - We should.
不 求求你不要跟我分手
No, please don't break up with me.
你是 你是全世界最睿智的
You're the -- the smartest,
最美的姑娘
most beautiful girl on the planet.
好吧
Fine.
我现在就给安迪发短信
I'm gonna text Andy right now,
告诉他我们今天应该好好谈谈
and tell him we need to talk today,
你也该这么做
and you should, too.
我发不了短信给他
I can't text him.
在他的西班牙语成绩
He lost his phone privileges
提上来之前他家里不让他用手机
until he gets his Spanish grade back up,
我还是去操场逛两圈吧
but I'll just go hang around the playground
等他的儿童足球训练完再找他
till his kickball practice is over.
还好我跟你聊过了
I'm glad we talked.
我也是
Me too.
我们以后也要多联系
This is how we're gonna stay on track
还有以后的以后
for the rest of our lives --
都要一直相互诉说倾听
by always being there for each other.
他还玩儿童足球
He plays kickball?
还只是个器材管理员
Equipment manager.
既然我们在学习如何积极沟通
Now that we're learning to communicate constructively,
那就试试这些新的沟通技巧吧
let's put those new skills to use.
谢谢
Thank you.
我想让每个人都写下
I want everyone to write down
你伴侣所做过每一件让你暴走的事情
everything about your partner that drives you crazy.
真的要写
Really?
抽屉都拉开了 就好好刨吧
The drawers are open. Dig in.
有点婚姻终结者的意思 对吧
Sounds a little marriage-endy, doesn't it?
是有点 但是对我们俩不起作用
I mean, it does, but not for us.
应该吧
Maybe...
有意思
Interesting.
菲尔 你不想吐槽克莱尔点什么吗
Phil, there's nothing that bugs you about Claire?
并没有
Nope.
比如说"偶稀饭[我喜欢]"
Not even "Me likey"?
-他在说什么 -我不知道
- What's he talking about? - I have no idea.
他说你老是说这句 搞得他要暴走
He says you say it a lot and it drives him crazy.
菲尔
Phil.
好吧 克莱尔 是的
Okay, uh, Claire. Yeah.
-我是爱你的 -我知道
- I love you. - I know.
但是每次你一那么说
But when you use that expression,
都让我感觉 很恶心
it makes me feel, um...icky.
但是 我从来都没有那么说过
But, I mean, I've hardly ever even used the expression --
"偶稀饭寿司 偶稀饭《权力的游戏》"
"Me likey sushi, me likey 'Game of Thrones'",
"偶稀饭喝夏敦埃酒"
"Me likey Chardonnay".
我听了真的受不了 但是 无所谓了
It does hit my ear wrong. But you know what? Forget it.
对不起 我没有要吐槽她的事情
I'm sorry. I got nothing to complain about.
偶幸运哟
Me lucky.
菲尔 你永远不必为自己的情感而道歉
Phil, never apologize for your feelings.
我们不是不该说"永远不"吗
I thought we're not supposed to say "Never".
说得对 杰 谢谢提醒
Good catch, Jay. Thank you.
就像年轻人说的那样 接下来我们要玩真的了
As the kids say, it's going to get real up in here,
但是你们要相信我 结束以后
but trust me, after that,
只要你们跟着我学会最具体的步骤
once I've guided you through the extremely specific steps
能够决定哪些情感要保留
in deciding what goes back in the drawer
哪些情感要摒弃
and what gets thrown out,
你们就会成为更好的自己
you will be the best version of yourselves.
-这方法总是有效 -不能说"总是"哦
- It always works. - Don't say "Always".
谢谢你
Thank you.
大家开始写吧
Let's get writing.
敞开了写
Nothing is off-limits.
这些是你们的私人想法
These are your private thoughts,
你们有权拥有这些想法
and you are entitled to them.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
你觉得我嗓门很大
You think I'm too loud?
我怎么就嗓门大了
How am I loud?
你吸气太足了
Well, you take in too much air
然后你瞬间就大力地把气呼出来了
and you expel that air with large and sudden bursts.
就这么回事
That's how.
所以你就是说我全身是气[说大话]
Oh, so you're saying that I am full of hot air?
不 我的意思正好相反
No, I'm saying just the opposite.
你说话都不留一口气
None of the air stays in you.
又是那灯的事 你现在还要把它写下来
The lights again. Now you've written it down?
我已经尽量不把事情写大了
I'm trying to stick to the small stuff.
好哇 恭喜你
Oh, well, congratulations.
你做到了 因为那件的确是小事
You nailed it, because that's real small.
但是它 它真的让我很烦 行吗
It -- okay, it bothers me, all right?
我已经非常好脾气地问你能不能关灯了
I-I've asked you very nicely to turn off the lights.
你那轮番轰炸
Constantly.
好像我们是不停躲避空袭的伦敦人
It's like we're Londoners hiding from war planes.
你干嘛要写"圆锥帐篷梗"
Why did you write down "Teepee joke"?
黛布拉说了 这些是我自己私人的想法
Debra said these are my personal and private thoughts.
我超爱那个梗 我经常讲 超搞笑
I love that joke. I tell it all the time. It's funny.
你觉得搞笑而已
To you.
好 听好了各位
Okay. Listen up, guys.
这个人走进他心理医生的办公室说
This guy walks into his shrink's office and he says,
"医生 我这是怎么了"
"Doc, what's wrong with me?"
"我是圆锥帐篷[勃起] 我是小棚屋[秃顶]"
"I'm a teepee. I'm a wigwam."
然后医生说
And the doc says,
"那正是问题所在 你是两顶帐篷[太紧张]"
"That's your problem. You're two tents."
懂了吗 两顶帐篷[太紧张]
Do you get it? Two tents.
笑话太糟了 克莱尔 太糟糕了
That's bad, Claire. That's really bad.
是你让她变成这样的
You made her like that.
如果你允许她有自己的感受
If you let her feel things,
也许她就能知道搞笑是什么感觉了
maybe she'll know what is funny.
懒得理你们
Don't care what you people think.
偶稀饭
Me likey.
这么说到底有什么问题
What is wrong with "Me likey"?
-克莱尔 -是
- Claire... - Yes.
-我是爱你的 -那就别一直说
- I love you. - Oh, then stop saying it!
-就是感觉那句话有点幼稚 -是吗
- It just seems a little childish. - Really?
因为你才是那个
'Cause you're the one
踩弹簧高跷踩到停不下来的那个人
who can't stop playing with his pogo stick.
如果你偶尔玩玩我的弹簧高跷[丁丁]
You know what? Maybe you'd be happier
也许你会更开心一点
if you played with my pogo stick once in a while.
噢 我天
Oh, my god!
太可悲了 他们居然在为弹簧高跷吵
What's sad is they're actually talking about a pogo stick.
可悲的应该是你爱省电多过爱我
What's sad is you love electricity more than me.
你就好像一个疯疯癫癫的小学二年级生
It's like we have a deranged second grader
天天在家附近跳来跳去
bouncing around the neighborhood.
你什么时候心态这么老了
When did you get so old?!
我是说 我是爱你的
I mean, I love you!
好了 小卡
All right, Cam,
我从小就特别不能忍受不关灯浪费电
It's been a pet peeve of mine since I was a kid,
而且我说过很多次了 你还无视我
and I've asked you so many times that when you ignore me,
我就有了消极攻击性的情绪
It feels a little passive-aggressive.
然后当你一直不停跟我念叨的时候
And when you nag me constantly,
我就感觉好像在跟老妈说话
it feels like I'm talking to my mother.
当我不得不对你碎碎念的时候
When I have to nag you,
我也感觉我像是你老妈
it makes me feel like I am your mother,
也许这就是为什么
which could be why it's been a month
我们已经有一个月没互相玩弹簧高跷[丁丁]了
since we played with each other's pogo sticks.
噢 我的老天
Oh, my god!
你觉得我们受得了吗 米奇尔
How do you think we feel, Mitchell?!
小姐 现在我们的方向都跑偏了
Miss, this is not going the way it should be.
你要不要告诉我们该怎么解决
Why don't you tell us how to fix this?
很抱歉 我得走了
I'm so sorry. I have to go.
不行 绝对不行
No, no, no!
你得帮我们收拾一下这局面
You have to help us put this back together!
我家里有急事
It's a family emergency.
相信我吧 你家不可能比我们这儿更糟
Trust me, it cannot be as bad as this one.
对不起 很抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
但是我得去接我儿子
But I have to go pick up my son
因为我那傻逼前夫把他的车借给了
because my idiot ex-husband loaned his car
他在陌陌上新认识的小贱人
to his latest Tinder whore.
我们可是花了一大笔钱的
We paid good money for this.
不 84美元而已
No, it was only $84.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我本来要给更多的 但是没人出价了
I would've paid more, but nobody else was bidding.
挺好
That's great.
我也就值这么多了
You know what? I deserve it.
把30年的研究成果简化成废物抽屉的比喻
This is what you get for dumbing down 30 years of research
也就只能值这个价了
for a trite analogy of a junk drawer.
就因为我的主编告诉我
Just because my editor told me
这样我就能上《艾伦秀》[著名脱口秀]录节目
it would get me on the "Ellen" Show.
你上过《艾伦秀》
You were on "Ellen"?
是的
Oh, yeah, yeah.
我曾经在全美家喻户晓
I danced my way into America's heart,
然后沦落到周日下午为80美元困在这里
and that's why I'm stuck here on a Sunday afternoon for 80 bucks.
等等 你现在不能走
Wait. You can't leave now.
废物全都挪出来了
All our junk is out!
衣服不错 看上去挺好的
That's a cool shirt. You look nice.
我得让你打住了
I have to cut you off right there.
这次我不会脱掉它的
The shirt stays on.
咱们不能再约炮了
I have to hang up on this booty call.
等等 你说什么
Wait, what?
你和我的这件事必须结束了
You and me, this -- this has to stop.
我深受罪恶感折磨
I'm so racked with guilt.
我不断给不同的慈善机构捐钱
I keep giving money to different charities.
我甚至还参加了一部扎克·布拉夫电影的众筹
I even fronted a Zach Braff movie on kickstarter.
安迪 慢点
Andy, slow down.
不 你没法说服我的
No, you're not gonna talk me into it.
我甚至穿了条难看的内裤以防万一
I'm even wearing embarrassing underwear just in case.
天啊 你可算让我轻松了
Oh, god, you're making this so much easier.
听着 我给你发了短信 意义一样
Look, I texted you to say the same thing.
-真的吗 -真的
- You did? - Yeah.
我想变成一个更优秀的人
I'm trying to be a better person.
你是我想变优秀的原因之一 然而
And, ironically, you're one of the reasons why, but...
一个优秀的人不能和已经订婚的人勾勾搭搭
A better person does not hook up with an engaged person.
那现在怎么办呢
So, what now?
不知道
I don't know.
我们还会互相见面
We're still gonna see each other.
你要给我半数的家人工作
You work for, like, half my family.
我该把你从我的呼叫圈[通话列表]上移除吗
Do I remove you from my calling circle?
那是你和你的WiFi携带仪[手机]之间的事了
I think that's between you and your wireless carrier.
看来就这样了
I guess that's that.
又不是要永别
It's not like it's goodbye forever.
只不过
It's just...
从现在起如果我们碰到对方
When we run into each other from now on,
要把衣服好好穿着
we keep our clothes on.
必须的
Yes. Totally.
但是
But, you know...
如果能重来
If things were different --
我懂
I know.
再见 海莉
Bye, Haley.
再见
Bye.
就这样结束了吗
So, that's it? It's over?
真不敢相信她就这么走了
I can't believe she just left like that.
那现在怎么办
Great. Now what?
我知道你们怎么想的
I know what you're all thinking,
好吧 我来引导大家
and, yes, I will take over as group leader.
没人这么想
No one's thinking that.
我是唯一一个有救场经历的人
I'm the only one with improv experience.
真的
Oh, really?
难道我就不是嘻哈黑羊组合中唯一白人成员了吗
Or was I the only white member of Ha Ha Blacksheep?
我依稀记得我通过模仿一位恐慌的游客
I seem to remember bringing down the hizouse
四分卫和布莱恩特·冈贝尔[美国记者]
with such classic characters as a scared tourist,
博得满堂彩
Quarterback, and Bryant Gumbel.
需要你的时候我会叫你的 大家注意
I'll tag you in if I need you. All right, everyone.
第一个练习叫作"进进出出"
This first exercise is called entrances and exits.
先让我说
Let me go first.
我要去看橄榄球比赛了
I'm leaving to watch the football game.
不行 杰 不准走
No, senor! Jay, no.
上苍啊
Oh, dear god!
我们之所以被搞得一团糟
The only reason we stirred all this up
全是因为迷糊眼女士
is 'cause Mrs. Magoo here
以为她竞拍的是真正收拾抽屉的服务
thought she was bidding on a home organizer.
我当时清楚我在干什么
I knew exactly what I was doing!
我试过各种方法了
I have tried everything.
我只不过需要一种新方式让你表达自己的情感
I just needed a new way to get you to express your feelings
让你学会倾听他人的情感
and to allow other people to express theirs.
我想让你理解并允许
I need you to be fine
曼尼开心的时候想在客厅跳舞就跳
with Manny dancing around the living room when he's happy
乔伤心的时候想哭就哭
and Joe crying when he's sad.
-你没看到这件事的负面影响吗 -没有
- You don't see the downside to all this? - No.
米奇尔 想说两句吗
Mitchell, you want to weigh in here?
我们都开始释放情感吧
We're all reliving it.
你俩怎么样
How about you two?
把话都说出来有没有感觉到舒畅很多
You feel good about getting all this stuff out in the open?
就让我把一件事解释清楚
Let me just make one thing perfectly clear.
有两顶帐篷[太紧张]
There were two tents.
帐篷和紧 你说对了
T-e-n-t-s and t-e-- you're right.
是个糟糕的笑话 但都是你的错
It's a horrible joke. But it's all your fault.
我就说吧
I told you!
再提一句 一想到异性恋发生关系
For the record, we are just as grossed out
我们也会感到恶心
at the thought of you all having sex --
够了 我走了 我们到底在搞什么
That's it! I'm out! What the hell are we doing?
像睡衣派对上的女孩一样手舞足蹈 分享秘密
Dancing around, telling secrets like girls at a slumber party.
我完全能想象我老爹和他的伙计们
I can just imagine my old man with his buddies
坐在躺椅上笑掉大牙
sitting at their lawn chairs, laughing their asses off
因为我错过了一整天的橄榄球赛
that I missed a whole day of football
为的是要弄清楚自己的情感
'cause I'm trying to get in touch with my emotions.
这些老家伙才不鸟这种屁事儿 他们是男人
These guys didn't do that crap. These were men!
他最好的朋友汤米·瑞恩
His best friend Tommy Ryan
被冲压机砸掉了半根指头
lost half a finger in a sheet metal press.
等到自己的工作结束才去的医院
Waited until his shift ended to go to the hospital.
我在橄榄球赛里撞碎了锁骨
I broke my collar bone in a football game.
老爹在台上给我说了那句老掉牙的"顶住"
There was Dad up in the stands giving me the old "be tough."
所以我撑过了两档进攻才晕了过去
So I played two more downs before I passed out.
我的女伴 玛丽乔·克朗姆斯基
My date, Maryjo Klumsky,
在毕业舞会上跟别的人跑了
left the senior dance with another guy.
我的心都碎了
Broke my heart.
凌晨两点 我老爹在餐桌上告诉我
2:00 A.M. at the kitchen table, my old man's telling me,
"吃个三明治然后把她忘掉"
"Eat the sandwich and forget about her."
情感
Feelings!
我居然没在他的葬礼上落泪 简直难以置信
I didn't even cry at his funeral. You believe that?
那家伙是我的全部
The guy was my whole world.
而我一滴泪也没流
Not a tear.
大家都望着我 觉得我好像并不爱他
Everybody looking at me like -- like I didn't love him.
但他懂的
But he knew.
他肯定懂的 对吧
He had to know, right?
他当然懂了
Of course he did.
该死的 释放出来还真是爽
Son of a bitch, that felt good getting that out.
是啊
I know.
成功的[一个]心理治疗[上个笑话的同音梗]
They just won therapy.
是我 我和罗本分手了
Hey, it's me. I broke up with reuben.
我知道他肯定会悲痛欲绝
I knew he'd be crushed,
所以我速战速决
so I did it quickly like ripping off
好像撕掉绿巨人创口贴一样
one of his Incredible Hulk band-aids.
你怎么样 搞定了吗
So, how about you? Did you do it?
搞了 肯定是搞了
Yep. I sure did.
为何我们要选择与我们相差甚远的人做伴侣
"Why do we choose partners so different from ourselves?
并非命运或是机遇
It's not fate or chance
也并非俗话所谓的"心意难违"
or cliches like 'the heart wants what the heart wants'."
我们选择了现在的伴侣是因为
"We choose our partners because they represent
他们代表了童年缺失的部分
the unfinished business from our childhood."
菲尔
Phil.
我们选择他们
"And we choose them
是因为他们有着我们渴望拥有的品质
because they manifest the qualities we wish we had."
我觉得对你来说我不够有趣
I'm afraid I'm not fun enough for you.
没错
Yeah.
我的口头禅不讨人喜欢 我的笑话不搞笑
My sayings aren't cute, my jokes aren't funny, and --
孩子离家之后你会厌倦我
And you're gonna get sick of me once the kids leave
你会发现我有多么疯狂
and you realize how truly crazy I am.
真的吗
Really?
亲爱的 我已经知道你有多疯狂了
Honey, I already know how crazy you are.
如此一来 如此地选择了区别甚大的伴侣
"In doing so, in choosing such a challenging partner,
并努力地给他们提供他们想要的东西
and working to give them what they need,
我们为自己的成长规划好了方向
we chart a course for our own growth."
睡吧 杰杰
Go to sleep, Jay-Jay.
说真的 那姐们儿真是个天才
I'm telling you, the woman is a genius.
那个周日我不想去我爷爷家
I didn't feel like going to my grandpa's house that sunday,
所以我就装作感冒了
so I pretended to have a cold.
没想的是 几天之后
Wouldn't you know it, a few days later...
不会吧
Oh, no.
没错 我真的感冒了
Yep. I got the cold.
我还以为这是报应 所以我跨上自行车
I thought it was karma, so I hopped on my bike
飞驰到了爷爷家
and I rode straight to my grandpa's.